Guide to the Michael M. Dawida Papers, 1984-1995 AIS.2000.02
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Michael M. Dawida Papers
1984-1995
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Dawida, Michael M.
AIS.2000.02
8 Linear Feet (13 boxes)
This collection documents the legislative career of Pennsylvania House of Representative Member (1979-1984) and later Pennsylvania State Senator, Michael (Mike) M. Dawida (D-Carrick), from 1985 to 1995. The collection mostly covers his career as State Senator (1989-1995). The materials in this collection are legislative files which were used to draft pieces of legislation; subject files of the various public issues that concerned Dawida; news releases; correspondence; videotapes of "Senate Journal," a television program hosted by Dawida, and various other videotapes of appearances by the Senator.
Biography
Michael (Mike) M. Dawida was born September 4, 1949 in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. He attended Carrick High School and then went to the University of Pittsburgh, from which he graduated in 1971 with a Bachelor of Arts degree. Dawida became a child care worker who worked with drug addicts and delinquent teenagers from 1969 to 1977. He later earned his J.D. at Hamline School of Law in St. Paul, Minnesota. He returned to Pittsburgh and worked as an attorney from 1977 to 1978. Dawida was first elected to the Pennsylvania House of Representatives in 1979 as a Democrat from the Carrick District. In his career as a Representative (1979-1984), Dawida sponsored the Clean Indoor Air Act, which sought to regulate smoking in public places. The law was responsible for creating separate smoking and non-smoking sections in restaurants. Initially, the bill was unpopular with the public and Dawida's fellow legislators, passing by only one vote. Since then the Clean Indoor Air Act has been expanded to restrict smoking in restaurants and bars.
Dawida was elected to the Pennsylvania Senate in 1989 and served in this capacity until 1995. During his career as a State Senator, he was concerned with improving health and welfare conditions for residents of Pennsylvania. He introduced and sponsored the Pennsylvania Food Donor Act, which made it easier for restaurants to donate leftover food to food banks and shelters without fear of lawsuits. He brought attention to the growing homeless population in Pennsylvania's cities. He introduced and authored the landmark Pennsylvania Organ Donation Act, which encouraged the donation of organs by registering when applying for drivers' licenses. This act was used as the national model for organ donation legislation. He also focused on the economic development of the commonwealth by establishing the Pennsylvania International Partners in Progress to open markets in Eastern Europe.
In 1996 Dawida was elected to the Allegheny County Board of Commissioners where he served until 2000 when a new Home Rule form of government became law. He served as its last Chairman of the Board from mid 1998 to 2000. Among his contributions as Commissioner was orchestrating several billion dollars of development projects which included Heinz Field, PNC Park, the Convention Center, and a multitude of other projects, such as the Waterfront shopping area in Homestead.
Scope and Content Notes
The papers of Michael M. Dawida pertain to his career as a politician in the Pennsylvania Legislature from 1984 to 1995. The bulk of the collection (1989-1995) focuses on his career as a State Senator. The collection contains a variety of material including legislative files used to draft legislation; subject files Dawida kept to research public issues; news releases; correspondence; videotapes of "Senate Journal," a local television program hosted by Senator Dawida, and other media appearances. Areas of concentration are insurance reform, homelessness, free trade, tobacco and smoking legislation, organ donation, and health and welfare issues.
Arrangement
Series I. Legislative Files, 1985-1989
Series II. Subject Files, 1984-1991
Series III. News Releases, 1985-1995
Series IV. Correspondence, 1985-1993
Series V. "Senate Journal" Television Program, 1989-1995
Series VI. Media Appearances, 1988-1995
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Michael M. Dawida in February 2000.
Previous Citation
Michael M. Dawida Papers, 1984-1995, AIS.2000.02, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh.
Economic development projects -– Pennsylvania -– Allegheny County; Public welfare -- Pennsylvania -- Law and legislation; Public health -- Pennsylvania -- Law and legislation; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Social action; Allegheny County (Pa.) -- Politics and government -- 20th century; Politicians; Personal papers; Omsk (Russia); Politics; Lawyers; Pennsylvania -- Politics and government -- 20th century; Lawyers -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Legislators; Legislators -- Pennsylvania; County officials and employees –- Pennsylvania -– Allegheny County; Politicians -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Dawida, Michael M.; Allegheny County (Pa.). Board of Commissioners; Pennsylvania. General Assembly. Senate; Pennsylvania. General Assembly. House of Representatives
- Legislative Files, 1985-1995; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series dates between 1985 and 1995 and contains files used by Senator Dawida to introduce and draft legislation in the Pennsylvania House and Senate. The legislative series also includes information on the various committees Senator Dawida served on during his tenure in the Senate. The material is arranged chronologically.
  - Health and Welfare Committee Materials, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Information on House Bill 577 Dangerous Juvenile Offenders, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Commission on Sentencing Guidelines, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Pennsylvania Legislative Children's Caucus, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allegheny County Legislative Package, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Pennsylvania Commission on Crime and Delinquency, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Subcommittee on Welfare, Mental Health/Retardation Organizations and Information, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Punitive Damages Legislation, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Catastrophic Loss Trust Fund (CAT Fund), 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Legislation Sponsorship Memos, 1985, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Department of Education, Subsidies for Education and Summary of New Legislation effecting Education, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Capital Budget and General Fund, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Proposed Amendments to Funeral Director Law, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Pennsylvania House of Representatives Review of Key Legislation Passed, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Welfare Subcommittee Files, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Information on House Bill 68, Nursing Home Reimbursement, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Amendments to the Divorce Code, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Co-Sponsored Legislation, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Blind Person Pension Legislation, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Information on House Resolution 22, Practices of Discount Beer, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Smoking Legislation, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Local Tax Reform, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Pennsylvania Infrastructure Investment Authority (PennVest), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Department of Commerce, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Public Health and Welfare Committee, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Organ Donor Legislation, Public Hearing Testimony, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Steel Valley Enterprise Zone Check Presentation, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Organ Donor Legislation Newspaper clippings, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Baseball Stadium Lottery Tax Fund Legislation, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Baseball Stadium Lottery Tax Fund Newspaper clippings, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - East European Task Force, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Members of East European Task Force Photograph, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Senate Farewell Message, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Subject Files, 1984-1992; II.
  The subject files were materials kept of constituent concerns from Senator Dawida's home district. This series includes information on the Steel Valley area, distressed communities, homelessness in Pennsylvania cities, health care costs, and restoration of industrial areas. Of particular interest are information and a proposal to build a high speed train across Pennsylvania, which would bring skilled technological jobs to the region and connect the state's largest cities. For more information on Maglev, please see Series VI, Box 11, Folders 4-5. The material in this series ranges in dates between 1984 to 1991 and is arranged chronologically.
  - Munhall Borough, 1984-1988 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Multi-skill Program Advisory Committee, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Distressed Communities in the Pittsburgh Area, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Health Care Costs, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Nursing Home Complaints, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - VisionQuest in Pennsylvania Investigation, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Notch Problem, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Steel Valley United for Economic Progress, Inc., By-Laws and Incorporation, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Liability Insurance Issues, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Baldwin Borough, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Homeless in Pittsburgh, 1985, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Southwestern Pennsylvania Pre-Trial Services Agency, Inc., 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Homestead Borough, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Nuclear Energy Information, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Legislative Office for Research Liaison (LORL) Joint Underwriting Association, , 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - West Run Road Creek Issue (Munhall, Pennsylvania), 1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Western Regional Reconstruction Redevelopment Commission, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Philadelphia Homeless, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Harrisburg Homeless, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Interim Report on Homelessness in Pennsylvania, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Industrial Capital Fund, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Hayes Flooding Problem, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Mon-Valley Expressway, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Legislative Office for Research Liaison (LORL), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Steel Valley Council of Governments (COG), 1987 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Homelessness, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Pennsylvania Homeless Newspaper clippings, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Steel Valley Authority Meeting Minutes and Newspapers clippings, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Final Report on Homelessness in Pennsylvania, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Waste Recycling, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Adoption, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Contraceptive Study, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Baldwin Borough, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Homestead Borough Planning Commission Grant, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Braddock Borough, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Schenley Park Restoration, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Turtle Creek Flood Control Rehabilitation Project, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Braddock Expressway Report, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Steel Industry Heritage Task Force, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Maglev High Speed train Proposal, 1990, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Weatherization Task Force, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- News Releases, 1985-1995; III.
  The news releases series contain press releases issued by Senator Dawida's office on pieces of legislation. Also included are newspaper clippings chronicling legislation and subjects related to his legislative interests and activities, such as the public's reaction to his Organ Donor and Tobacco legislation. The series also has material related to press conferences held by the Senator's office. The material is arranged chronologically from 1985 to 1995.
  - News Releases, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - News Releases, January-December 1986 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Newspaper Clippings, Gary Hart's visit at Rainbow Kitchen, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - News Releases on Homelessness, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - News Releases, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Tobacco Legislation New Releases and Newspaper clippings, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - News Releases, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - News Releases, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Child-Care Legislation Press Conference, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - School Breakfast Legislation Press Conference, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Maglev Caucus Press Conference, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - News Releases, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Pittsburgh Public Schools Food Donations Press Conference, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - News Releases, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Omsk, Siberia Trip Press Conference, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - News Releases, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Organ Donor Legislation Press Releases, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Correspondence, 1985-1993; IV.
  This series, which dates between 1985 and 1993, contains correspondence relating to Senator Dawida's work and interest in the Pennsylvania Legislature. The correspondence is most plentiful for 1985 and 1986 and organized by month. Later dates are kept by year. Included is a sampling of constituent correspondence, from which every third letter was retained. The correspondence series also includes letters the Senator wrote to the newspaper, The Pittsburgh Press, memos sent to Senate members about sponsoring legislation, and correspondence on budget matters.
  - Memos sent to all House members, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Letters to The Pittsburgh Press, 1985, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence, January 1985 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, February 1985 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence, March 1985 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence, April 1985 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence, May 1985 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence, June 1985 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence, July 1985 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, August 1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, September 1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, October 1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, November 1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, December 1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, January 1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, February 1986 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, March 1986 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, April 1986 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, May 1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, June 1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, July 1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, August 1986 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, September 1986 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, October 1986 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, November 1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, December 1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Budget Correspondence, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Organ Donor Legislation Correspondence, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- "Senate Journal" Television Program, 1989-1995; V.
  "Senate Journal" was a local television program hosted by Senator Dawida. The program sought to inform constituents on important local and public issues and the activities of the Legislature in Harrisburg. The "Senate Journal" series dates between 1988 and 1995 and is arranged chronologically. All "Senate Journal" programs are on VHS cassette tapes and can be viewed at the Archives Service Center.
  - Senate Journal" Planning Memos, June- November 1990 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - "Senate Journal" Planning Memos, January-December 1991 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - "Senate Journal" Planning Memos, January-December 1992 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Guest: Honorable Karen A. Miller, December 21, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Guest: Alfred M, Manganiello, January 25, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Guest: Rev. Ronald Sell, February 13, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Guest: Lt. Governor Mark Singel, March 14, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Mental Health, June 20, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: South Side Pittsburgh Revitalization, July 26, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: PA State Parks System, August 15, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Aging, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Prisons, December 6, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Aging, November 29, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Solid Waste/Recycling, September 27, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania's Economy, January 3, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Drugs, February 13, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Education, October 24, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Prisons, December 6, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Aging, February 13, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: 1990 Proposed Budget, March 26, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania's Environment, May 22, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Transportation in Pennsylvania, November 12, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pittsburgh Commercial Food Bank and Auto Insurance Law", April 24, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Aging in Pennsylvania, June 18, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Tourism in Pennsylvania, June 28, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Military and Veterans Affairs, August 28, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Energy and Energy Conservation, October 2, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania Treasury, June 3, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania State Parks, July 2, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Law and Order in PA, July 25, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Consumer Issues, December 17, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania's Recycling Law, Act 101, January 30, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Health Issues in Pennsylvania, March 13, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania's Correctional System, April 9, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania Lottery, May 14, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Greater Pittsburgh Community Food Bank and Pennsylvania's New Auto Insurance Law, , undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: The Rising Cost of Health Insurance, January 14, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Workers' Compensation and Worker Safety, January 29, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Balancing the Budget and the 1992-1993 Pennsylvania Budget, April 8, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Doing Business with Business in Pennsylvania, May 12, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania Emergency Management Agency, June 9, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Transportation in Pittsburgh, September 22, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: The Impact of Professional Sports on Pittsburgh, October 19, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Children's Health Issues, November 10, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Drunk Driving Prevention and Prosecution, December 11, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania Department of Community Affairs, February 4, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania's Minority Business Development Authority, February 2, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania's Recycling Effort/ The New Frontier, January 27, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: The Pennsylvania Corps, May 11, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: 1993-1994 Pennsylvania State Budget Proposal and Organ Donation, April 20, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Organ Donation in Pennsylvania, August 31, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Family and Medical Leave, March 24, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Tips and Reminders for Older Pennsylvanians, June 8, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania State Police, September 28, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Task Force on Defense Related Industries, November 9, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: The Senate Democratic Report Card, November 22, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Travel and Tourism in Pennsylvania, June 22, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Department of General Services, July 21, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania Health Security Act, January 7, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Child Care in Pennsylvania, June 25, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Innovations in Education, February 1, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Crime and Violence in Pennsylvania, March 3, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: The State of the Commonwealth, April 4, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania International Partners in Progress, April 26, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: The 1994-1995 PA State Budget, April 27, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Children's Health Issues, August 4, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Senate Session June 28, 1994 Local Tax Reform Debate, , undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania State Parks, September 6, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Domestic Violence, October 3, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: International Trade- Marketing PA Worldwide, November 3, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Allegheny Regional Asset District, December 2, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: International Trade- Marketing PA Worldwide, November 3, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Reducing Pennsylvania's Personal Income Tax, March 27, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Health Issues of the Future, January 27, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - "Senate Journal" with Senator Dawida, Topic: Pennsylvania's District Court Justice System, February 27, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 14)